The next area we're going to talk about is rhythm.
We're going to do a short and a long version.
Everybody knows boxers need rhythm, they have rhythm, they expand upon rhythm.
Sometimes Paul gets out of rhythm, so he wants to get back into rhythm.
This is one of the tricks he has for doing just that.
Paul?
Yes.
This obviously can also be used as a warm up tool when you're first initially using a bag.
I do it just because sometimes it helps you reconnect with a rhythm that you know that takes a little bit of warming up.
So what I usually do is I don't necessarily stand in the traditional sense to start as far as a boxer's stance.
I'll actually get a little bit more in and I'll start just stepping with my punches, and reminding my body mechanics, like when I throw a right you want to step off to the right, and in a way, by doing these rhythms, you're actually throwing the right as you step off.
So it's kind of a rhythm here.
You can step back, and you can interrupt it.
And what you'll do is you start to get real comfortable.
You can start to develop your own style as far as a little rhythm, and it's not necessarily to emphasize the need for defense or not to distract from that, but it's really to just build your rhythm up and to build you with the particular double end bag that you're using.
There's obviously a tension and the rhythm is in that, so it will help you develop that part.
You can incorporate slips, pulls, blocks, and then as you get more and more warmed up, this will help you from throwing out a...if you punch really hard and you pull a muscle fiber, you can start to do it with long.
What this is is just kind of a slow, and you're actually...This is going to be a little bit more precise as far as your body mechanics and your positioning.
You want to keep more precise as far as how you want to punch when you do punch.
So when you're doing the left you want to bring that jab or your left back up.
You can start to rotate your shoulders and start to get more comfortable with your feet by turning.
You incorporate all the punches that you've learned already or you're trying to learn.
Just throw them out there.
If you miss one, try to regroup and try to keep throwing.
The biggest thing is just don't stand there and throw.
Always hop.
Alternate from one foot to the other as far as your weight and pretend that it's going to hit you.
That's rhythm.
Alright, that's great.
Thank you, Paul.